Mss.B.B445
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Freundlich, Herbert, 1939 February (Box 7, Folder 32)
    Freundlich, Herbert
    Letters in reference to finding a job in the United States for Dr. Marie Wrescher.
  - Frey, Ralph W., 1934 June - 1936 March (Box 7, Folder 33)
    Frey, Ralph W.
    Letters requesting a sample of salzstippen leather. Letters to Max Bergmann explaining Frey's work with leather. Letters requesting the chemical phosgene.
  - Fried, Josef, 1940 January - February (Box 7, Folder 34)
    Fried, Josef
    Letters from Josef Fried (German refugee) to Max Bergmann concerning employment.
  - Friedberg, A. E., 1942 March (Box 7, Folder 35)
    Friedberg, A. E.
    Letters concerning the delivery of cigars to Max Bergmann.
  - Fruton, Joseph S., No. 1, 1936 January - 1939 August (Box 7, Folder 36)
    Fruton, Joseph S., No. 1
    Personal correspondence between Max Bergmann and Joseph S. Fruton. Inlcudes notes about demonstrations Fruton has to give at his lab.
  - Fruton, Joseph S., No. 2, 1941 June - 1945 December (Box 7, Folder 37)
    Fruton, Joseph S., No. 2
    Personal correspondence. Work reports both to and from Max Bergmann and Joseph S. Fruton when both were on vacation. Requests for reprints. Fruton's curriculum vitae and bibliography up to 1942. Copy of a talk given by Max Bergmann on the occasion of Fruton being given the Eli Lilly Award in 1944. Speech given by Fruton at Bergmann's funeral.
  - Fruton, Joseph S., No. 3, 1939 January (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Fruton, Joseph S., No. 3
    Talk given at a staff meeting.
  - Fuchs, Karl, 1939 February (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Fuchs, Karl
    Letters concerning employment. A copy of Fuchs' curriculum vitae included.
  - Fuchs, Margaret U., 1939 October (Box 8, Folder 3)
    Fuchs, Margaret U.
  - G - Misc., No. 1, 1934 January - 1948 October (Box 8, Folder 4)
    G - Misc., No. 1
    General miscellaneous materials.
  - G - Misc., No. 2, 1934 June - 1944 August (Box 8, Folder 5)
    G - Misc., No. 2
    General miscellaneous material. Letters requesting reprints. Letter from Max Bergmann requesting a sample of Rhamnose. A newspaper article dated August 20, 1944, titled "Can the Germans Cure Themselves?"
  - G - Misc., No. 3, 1943 May (Box 8, Folder 6)
    G - Misc., No. 3
    General miscellaneous material. A letter of recommendation for Gertrude Glauber. References to other letters in the collection.
  - G - Misc., No. 4, 1937 November - 1944 June (Box 8, Folder 7)
    G - Misc., No. 4
    General miscellaneous material. Letters of inroduction. Requests and thanks for reprints. Invitations to speak at conferences.
  - G - Misc., No. 5, 1934 September - 1943 June (Box 8, Folder 8)
    G - Misc., No. 5
    Miscellaneous material. Letter to Adoph Grun in Swtizerland acknowledging that Max Bergmann had recieved his letter concerning a Dr. Brenner in Zurich and will accept Brenner in his lab for one year. Abstract of a lecture given by Bergmann titled, "Structure of Proteins in Relation to Biological Problems."
  - Gallay, W., 1938 January - 1943 November (Box 8, Folder 9)
    Gallay, W.
    Letters to Max Bergmann thanking him for reprints.
  - Gasser, Herbert S., No. 1, 1941 February - 1945 February (Box 8, Folder 10)
    Gasser, Herbert S., #1
    General correspondence between Max Bergman and Herbert S. Gasser (Director of the Rockefeller Institute). Invitations to dinner. Request for Bergmann's annual lab report. Notices of Institute meetings. Notes to Gasser from Bergmann regarding students working in his lab, including: William H. Stein, Paul Zamecnik, Robert Ballentine, E. Silva Roche, Mark A. Stahmann, and Calvin Golumbic. Notices of F. Goebel and Rene Dubois becoming members of the Rockefeller Institute.
  - Gasser, Herbert S., No. 2, 1936 May - 1940 November (Box 8, Folder 11)
    Gasser, Herbert S., No. 2
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Herbert S. Gasser (Director of the Rockefeller Institute).
  - Gilman, Henry, 1934 August - 1944 August (Box 8, Folder 12)
    Gilman, Henry
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Henry Gilman. Includes letters of recommendation and Bergmann's comments on chapters written by Gilman.
  - Glaser, Elizabeth B., 1940 January (Box 8, Folder 13)
    Glaser, Elizabeth B.
    Application for a job in Max Bergmann's lab. Includes a cover letter, resume, transcripts, letters of recommendation, and a photograph.
  - Glasser, Otto, 1941 April (Box 8, Folder 14)
    Glasser, Otto
    Correspondence between Max Bergmann and Otto Glaser concerning Bergmann's contribution to a book.
  - Glick, David, 1943 May (Box 8, Folder 15)
    Glick, David
    Letters concerning problems with an experiment. Includes a curriculum vitae and publications list for David Glick.
  - Globus, Joseph H., 1939 June - October (Box 8, Folder 16)
    Globus, Joseph H.
    Letters concerning the reprinting of an article written by Globus and max Bergmann in the "Journal of the Mount Sinai Hospital."
  - Goepp, R. Max, Jr., 1941 January - April (Box 8, Folder 17)
    Goepp, R. Max, Jr.
    Letters seeking the advice of Max Bergmann for a commemorative meeting to be held in St. Louis for Emil Fischer.
  - Goldberg, Joseph L., 1941 October - November (Box 8, Folder 18)
    Goldberg, Joseph L.
    Letters asking Max Bergmann to write a recommendation for Goldberg.
  - Goldschmiedt, Henry, 1941 May - 1943 May (Box 8, Folder 19)
    Goldschimiedt, Henry
    Letters asking Max Bergmann to join as an honorary member of the American Society of European Chemists and Pharmacists. Includes several pamphlets and programs for group meetings.
  - Goldstein, Kurt, 1938 November - 1939 September (Box 8, Folder 20)
    Goldstein, Kurt
    Correspondence between Max Bergmann and Kurt Goldstein in regards to refugee scientists. A letter from Bergmann concerning advice about to prospective refugees, Dr. V. Kaffka and Dr. Else Hirschberg, both about to be interned in Germany if not helped. A letter regarding an opening for two female refugees.
  - Gray, Philip P., 1941 March (Box 8, Folder 21)
    Gray, Phillip P.
    Letter about a sample of pepsin sent to Gray from Max Bergmann.
  - Greenberg, David M., 1941 May - 1944 October (Box 8, Folder 22)
    Greenberg, David M.
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and David Greenberg. Includes letters regarding experiments and requests for reprints.
  - Greenstein, Jesse P., No. 1, 1934 May - 1944 September (Box 8, Folder 23)
    Greenstein, Jesse P., No. 1
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Jesse P. Greenstein. Letters pertaining to reprints and samples of chemicals from Bergmann. Includes letters of recommendation written for Greenstein by Bergmann.
  - Greenstein, Jesse P., No. 2, 1941 October - 1944 June (Box 8, Folder 24)
    Greenstein, Jesse P., No. 2
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Jesse P. Greenstein.
  - Growth Society of Lankenau Hospital, 1942 May - 1944 March (Box 8, Folder 25)
    Growth Society of Lankenau Hospital
    The editors from the journal "Growth" write to Max Bergmann requesting an article.
  - Guggenheim, M., 1934 July - 1937 March (Box 8, Folder 26)
    Guggenheim, M.
    A letter announcing Max Bergmann's employment at the Rockefeller Institute. Letters regarding the purchase of various chemicals for experiments. Requests for reprints.
  - Gustavson, K. H., 1934 April - 1941 May (Box 8, Folder 27)
    Gustavson, K. H.
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Gustavson. Letters discuss the technical aspects of Gustavson's work with Max Bergmann. Requests for reprints.
  - Gutfeld, Fritz J. von, 1939 October - 1941 November (Box 8, Folder 28)
    Gutfeld, Fritz J. von
    Correspondence concerning the employment of Fritz J. von Gutfeld. Includes letters of recommendation from Max Bergmann and a curriculum vitae.
  - Gyorgy, Paul, 1937 November - 1942 October (Box 8, Folder 29)
    Gyorgy, Paul
    Letters concerning the search for young chemists to fill various positions at Gyorgy's lab.
  - H - Misc., No. 1, 1934 March - 1944 October (Box 8, Folder 30)
    H - Misc., No. 1
    General miscellaneous material.
  - H - Misc., No. 2, 1934 March - 1944 October (Box 8, Folder 31)
    H - Misc., No. 2
  - H - Misc., No. 3, 1934 March - 1944 October (Box 9, Folder 1)
    H - Misc., No. 3
  - H - Misc., No. 4, 1934 March - 1944 October (Box 9, Folder 2)
    H - Misc., No. 4
  - H - Misc., No. 5, 1934 March - 1944 October (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Haas, Otto H., 1934 April - 1936 April (Box 9, Folder 4)
    Haas, Otto H.
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Otto Haas. Letter asking Bergmann to be a consultant for Rohm and Haas Co. A leather sample sent from Haas to Bergmann.
  - Hack, Marvin H., 1944 April - 1945 February (Box 9, Folder 5)
    Hack, Marvin H.
    Letters concerning chemicals wanted by Hack.
  - Hale, D. R., 1938 February - March (Box 9, Folder 6)
    Hale, D. R.
    A letter of introduction for Miss Florence Edel.
  - Halliday, Nellie, 1942 February - 1943 February (Box 9, Folder 7)
    Halliday, Nellie
    Request for information on certain types of production for chemicals. Requests for reprints.
  - Hanson, Frank Blair, 1935 May - 1940 June (Box 9, Folder 8)
    Hanson, Frank Blair
    Information to Max Bergmann regarding the reciepts of fellowships by students that will be under his instruction.
  - Harrington, C. R., 1934 April - 1944 October (Box 9, Folder 9)
    Harrington, C. R.
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Harrington. Letters regarding Harrington's work at the University College Hospital Medical School at the University of London. A letter from Bergmann to Harrington introducing Carl Niemann. An invitation to meeting at the British Association for the Advancement of Science.
  - Harrow, Benjamin, 1937 December - 1941 October (Box 9, Folder 10)
    Harrow, Benjamin
    Requets for Max Bergman's reprints. A letter from Harrow asking Bergman and Joseph Fruton to review chapters of a new book. A letter from Bergmann to Harrow recommending Joseph I. Goldberger for a job.
  - Harte, Robert A., 1942 September - 1944 July (Box 9, Folder 11)
    Harte, Robert A.
    Request for reprints. A letter inviting Max Bergmann to address the Metropolitan Microchemical Society.
  - Harvey, Alexander, 1934 April - 1936 March (Box 9, Folder 12)
    Harvey, Alexander
    Correspondence concerning reprints.
  - Harvey Society, 1940 - 1943 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    Harvey Society
    Miscellaneous materials concerning the Harvey Society. Includes invitations to meetings, yearly schedules, and lecture cards.
  - Haugaard, Gotfred, No. 1, 1938 June - 1940 November (Box 9, Folder 14)
    Haugaard, Gotfred, No. 1
    Letters form max Bergmann informing Haugaard that he can come to work in Bergmann's lab on a Rockefeller Scholarship. Letters regarding the arrangements of his arrival. Letter of recommendation from Lindestrom-Lang of the Carlsberg Lab.
  - Haugaard, Gotfred, No. 2, 1941 April - 1944 April (Box 9, Folder 15)
    Haugaard, Gotfred, No. 2
    Personal correspondence informing Max Bergmann of Haugaard's progress and whereabouts after leaving Bergmann's lab. Biographical data about Haugaard, including his bibliography to 1941. A letter from Haugaard to Bergmann seeking advice on how to find permanent employment in the United States.
  - Haurowitz, Felix, 1937 May - 1943 August (Box 9, Folder 16)
    Haurowitz, Felix
    Correspondence between Max Bergmann and Haurowitz. Haurowitz writes from Istanbul seeking advice from Bergmann on a move to the United States.
  - Hayden, Philip M., 1936 September - 1939 March (Box 9, Folder 17)
    Hayden, Phillip M.
    Letters of recommendation written by Max Bergmann to Phillip Hayden at Columbia University.
  - Heidelberger, Michael, 1942 August - 1944 October (Box 9, Folder 18)
    Heidelberger, Michael
    Correspondence between Max Bergmann and Michael Heidelberger. Letter from Heidelberger and his son Charles to Max Bergmann in regards to a job in Bergmann's lab. Includes a letter from Charles Heidelberger informing Bergmann of his regrets in turning down a position in his lab. A letter of recommendation for Manfred Mayer from Michael Heidelberger to Max Bergman.
  - Hellerman, Leslie, 1935 November - 1943 February (Box 9, Folder 19)
    Hellerman, Leslie
    Requests for reprints from Max Bergmann.
  - Hess, Walter C., 1941 May (Box 9, Folder 20)
    Hess, Walter C.
    Questions concerning figures in one of Max Bergmann's articles.
  - Heymann, Karl, 1937 January - 1939 January (Box 9, Folder 21)
    Heymann, Karl
    A letter of recommendation written by Max Bergmann.
  - Hibbert, Harold, No. 1, 1941 April - 1943 October (Box 9, Folder 22)
    Hibbert, Harold, No. 1
    General correspondence between max Bergmann and Harold Hibbert. Hibbert seeks advice Bergmann on how to make a digestable membrane sheath to be used in surgery.
  - Hibbert, Harold, No. 2, 1934 January - 1940 November (Box 9, Folder 23)
    Hibbert, Harold, No. 2
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Harold Hibbert. Letter from Hibbert to Bergmann recommending a Dr. Herzog who is looking to leave Germany and find employment in the United States. A letter discussing the suicide of Herzog. Letters of recommendation from Hibbert regarding Dr. Saul Trister and W. Lincoln Hawkins. Letters of recommendation from Bergmann regarding Miss Vilma Prochaunick and Herbert Ellern-Eichmann.
  - Highberger, John H., 1935 September - 1944 June (Box 9, Folder 24)
    Highburger, John H.
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and John Highburger. Invitations to dinner. Letters regarding technical advice and information about experiments.
  - Hirschberg, Else, 1939 January - June (Box 9, Folder 25)
    Hirschberg, Else
    Letters concerning a job for Hirschberg in the United States. Curriculum vitae included.
  - Hirschwaldsche Buchhandlung, 1934 August - 1935 June (Box 9, Folder 26)
    Hirschwaldsche Buchhandlung
    Book distributors in Germany. Letters from Bergmann requesting articles.
  - Hixon, R. M., 1942 July - 1943 January (Box 9, Folder 27)
    Hixon, R. M.
    Bergmann writes to Hixon looking for a young chemist to work at the Rockefeller Institute under him.
  - Hoffmann-LaRoche, Inc., 1936 October - 1944 April (Box 9, Folder 28)
    Hoffmann-LaRoche, Inc.
    Reprints, catalogs of chemicals for sale. Letters of recommendation from Max Bergmann.
  - Hofmann, Klaus, 1938 February - 1943 November (Box 9, Folder 29)
    Hofmann, Klaus
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Klaus Hofmann. Letters of recommendation for Hoffmann. Letters concerning Hofmann's work as a fellow at the Rockefeller Institute. Postcards to Bergmann from Hoffmann.
  - Hornicek, Frank, 1942 December - 1944 March (Box 9, Folder 30)
    Hornicek, Frank
    Personal correspondence between Max Bergmann and Frank Hornicek. Letters discuss the war effort at home and abroad. Bergmann sends letters of well wishes and cigars. Hornicek writes to Bergmann informing him of his progress in basic training and then in combat.
  - Horsfall, Frank L., 1941 September - 1943 January (Box 9, Folder 31)
    Horsfall, Frank L.
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Frank Horsfall. Letter informing Max Bergmann of his appointment to the Committee of the Staff Meetings of the Rockefeller Institute. Letters regarding staff meetings. A note of thanks for equipment lent by Bergmann to Horsfall.
  - Hotchkiss, Rollin D., 1943 October - 1944 April (Box 9, Folder 32)
    Hotchkiss, Rollin D.
    Letters requesting reprints.
  - Hotels, 1935 June - 1942 July (Box 9, Folder 33)
    Hotels
    General correspondence regarding hotel reservations and conferences.
  - Howard, Curt G., 1940 February - March (Box 9, Folder 34)
    Howard, Curt G.
    Letters from Howard to Max Bergmann seeking advice on finding a job.
  - Hunter, Andrew, 1937 December - 1941 June (Box 9, Folder 35)
    Hunter, Andrew
    Letters concerning analytical work and requests for chemicals.
  - Hurd, Charles D., 1939 October - 1942 August (Box 9, Folder 36)
    Hurd, Charles D.
    Max Bergmann writes requesting reports on the work of the Committee on Carbohydrate Nomenclature of the American Chemical Society. Letters from Bergmann to Hurd concerning the need for young chemists available to work in his lab.
  - I - Misc., 1934 April - 1944 November (Box 10, Folder 1)
    I - Misc.
    Miscellaneous materials.
  - Ignatieff, V., 1934 August - 1938 February (Box 10, Folder 2)
    Ignatieff, V.
    Letters requesting Max Bergmann's reprints.
  - Ing, Harold R., 1938 May - 1939 November (Box 10, Folder 3)
    Ing, Harold R.
    Letters concerning arrangements to work in Max Bergamnn's lab. A letter accepting a Rockefeller Institute scholarship.
  - Institute of Leather Manufacture Research, 1934 September - 1937 March (Box 10, Folder 4)
    Institute of Leather Manufacture Research
    Letters requesting reprints. Includes a copy of "Technology of the Tanning Extract Manufacture," written by M. I. Haydyk.
  - International Physiological Congress, 1935 August - 1938 August (Box 10, Folder 5)
    International Physiological Congress
    Notices of meetings and brochures for the International Physiological Conference held in the Soviet Union and Switzerland.
  - Interscience Publishers Incorporated, 1940 October - 1944 July (Box 10, Folder 6)
    Interscience Publishers Incorporated
    General correspondence. Business letters, returning and reprinting of proofs, copies of reprints sent to Max Bergmann, book lists, and bills.
  - Invitations, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
    Invitations
    Invitations to events including handwritten notes of "accepted" or "declined."
  - Irving, George W., Jr., 1942 February - 1944 February (Box 10, Folder 8)
    Irving, George W., Jr.
    Informal letters about Irving's move to New Orleans. A note about Otto Loewy's son, a refugee residing in Peru who may get a visa to the United States, Max Bergmann asks if Irving will be of some help when he passes through New Orleans.
  - Isabell, Horace S., 1942 October - 1944 April (Box 10, Folder 9)
    Isabell, Horace S.
    Correspondence between Max Bergmann and Horace Isabell concerning a speech given by Max Bergmann to the Washington Section of the American Chemical Society. Letters asking Bergmann to read an article and a manuscript written by Isabell.
  - Isolation of P-Serine From Silk Fibroins, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
    Isolation of P-Serine From Silk Fibroins
    Driections for the Isolation of P-Serine From Silk Fibroins.
  - J - Misc., No. 1, 1941 June - 1943 December (Box 10, Folder 11)
    J - Misc., No. 1
    General miscellaneous materials. Letters requesting reprints and chemical samples. Curriculum vitae of Lillian Ann Jedeikin.
  - J - Misc., No. 2, 1935 June - 1944 June (Box 10, Folder 12)
    J - Misc., No. 2
    General miscellaneous materials. Letters discussing experiements, requests for reprints, and letters regarding positions in Max Bergmann's lab. Letter of recommendation written by Bergmann for Jesse P. Greenstein.
  - Jablonski, Ludwig, 1941 September (Box 10, Folder 13)
    Jablonski, Ludwig
    Letters to Max Bergmann concerning employment in the United States.
  - Jackson, Richard W., 1939 October - 1945 October (Box 10, Folder 14)
    Jackson, Richard W.
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Richard Jackson. Letters discussing the organization of the protein Division of the Eastern Regional Research Labs. Requests for reprints. Bergmann writes to Jackson requesting information on David Doherty. A letter of recommendation for Dr. Emil L. Smith for an opening in Jackson's lab.
  - Jacobs, Walter A., 1945 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    Jacobs, Walter A.
    Bibliography of Walter A. Jacobs from 1906 - 1945
  - Jacoby, Kurt, 1943 January - 1944 September (Box 10, Folder 16)
    Jacoby, Kurt
    Letter from Max Bergmann vouching for Jacoby's charachter when he applies for a United States visa. Invitation to dinner at a publishing house.
  - Jambor, Nikolaus, 1934 June - 1939 December (Box 10, Folder 17)
    Jambor, Nikolaus
    Personal correspondence between Max Bergmann and Nikolaus Jambour.
  - Jameson, Eloise, 1941 June (Box 10, Folder 18)
    Jameson, Eloise
    Invitation to dinner when Max Bergmann attends a Stanford University meeting.
  - Janeway Lecture, 1939 May 16 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    Janeway Lecture
    Copy of the Edward Gamaliel Janeway Lecture, delivered by Max Bergmann at the Mount Sinai Hospital on May 16, 1939. The lecture is titled, "Some Biological Aspects of Protein Chemists."
  - Jewish Organizations, 1941 November - 1944 May (Box 10, Folder 20)
    Jewish Organizations
    Invitations to meetings and dinners for many Jewish Societies including the Federation of Jewish Charities, the United Jewish Appeal, and the American Jewish Committee.
  - Johns Hopkins University, 1937 June - 1941 June (Box 10, Folder 21)
    Johns Hopkins University
    Announcements for the "Johns Hopkins University Annual Research Conference." A letter of recommendation written by Max Bergmann on behalf of Dr. Alfred Reis. Letters from the New School for Social Research asking for a reference for Dr. Paul Erculisse.
  - Johnson, Walter J., 1944 October - 1945 October (Box 10, Folder 22)
    Johnson, Walter, J.
    A book dealer who Max Bergmann sells his used books. Later correspondence with between Johnson and Bergmann's secretary after his death.
  - Joseph, Rosalind, 1943 October (Box 10, Folder 23)
    Joseph, Rosalind
    Copy of a speech given by Max Bergmann at a party in honor of Rosalind Joseph.
  - Jourdan Lloyd, Dorothy, 1935 December - 1940 May (Box 10, Folder 24)
    Jordan Lloyd, Dorothy
    General correspondence. Requests for reprints. General notes of thanks. Letters concerning Lloyd's visit to Max Bergmann's lab on behalf of the British Leather Chemical Association.
  - Journal of Biological Chemistry, No. 1, 1944 April - 1945 March (Box 10, Folder 25)
    Journal of Biological Chemistry, No. 1
    Letters concerning the submission of papers to the Journal of Biological Chemistry.
  - Journal of Biological Chemistry, No. 2, 1942 September - 1944 April (Box 10, Folder 26)
    Journal of Biological Chemistry, No. 2
  - Journal of Biological Chemistry, No. 3, 1942 January - 1944 March (Box 10, Folder 27)
    Journal of Biological Chemistry, No. 3
    Max Bergmann's notes, analysis, and critiques of papers submitted to the Journal of Biological Chemistry.
  - Journal of Biological Chemistry, No. 4, 1935 January - 1940 August (Box 10, Folder 28)
    Journal of Biological Chemistry, No. 4
    Letters concerning the submission of papers to the Journal of Biological Chemistry. Includes a copy of a paper titled, "Aromatic Sulfonic Acids as Reagents for Amino Acids."
  - Journal of Biological Chemistry, No. 5, 1937 October - 1939 January (Box 11, Folder 1)
    Journal of Biological Chemistry, No. 5
    Letters concerning the submission of papers to the Journal of Biological Chemistry. Includes Max Bergmann's critques of several papers submitted.
  - Journal of Biological Chemistry, No. 6, 1937 May - 1940 January (Box 11, Folder 2)
    Journal of Biological Chemistry, No. 6
    Letters concerning the submission of papers to the Journal of Biological Chemistry. Includes a copy of a paper titled,"Resolution of dl-Phenylalanine."
  - Journal of Biological Chemistry, No. 7, 1939 December - 1940 April (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Journal of Biological Chemistry, No. 7
    Letters concerning the submission of papers to the Journal of Biological Chemistry. Includes a copy of a paper titled, "Preperation of d(-)- Glutamic Acid from dl-Glutamic Acid by Enzymatic Resolution."
  - Journal of Biological Chemistry, No. 8, 1939 July - 1940 November (Box 11, Folder 4)
    Journal of Biological Chemistry, No. 8